codeplex.com 2017-12-23

# CodePlex - Privacy Statement

### Last updated: March 2009

Microsoft is committed to protecting your privacy, while delivering software that brings you the performance, power, and convenience you desire in your personal computing. This privacy statement explains many of the data collection and use practices of Microsoft CodePlex (“CodePlex”). It focuses on features that communicate with the Internet. It does not apply to other online or offline Microsoft sites, products, or services. 

CodePlex is Microsoft's open source project hosting web site. CodePlex enables you to start a new project, join an existing one, or download software created by the community.

## Collection and Use of Your Information

The information we collect from you will be used by Microsoft and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates to enable the features you are using and provide the service(s) or carry out the transaction(s) you have requested or authorized. It may also be used to analyze and improve Microsoft products and services.

We may send certain mandatory service communications such as welcome letters, billing reminders, information on technical service issues, and security announcements. Some Microsoft services may send periodic member letters that are considered part of the service. We may occasionally request your feedback, invite you to participate in surveys, or send you promotional mailings to inform you of other products or services available from Microsoft and its affiliates. 

Except as described in this statement, personal information you provide will not be transferred to third parties without your consent. We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as packaging, sending and delivering purchases and other mailings, answering customer questions about products or services, processing event registration, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

Microsoft may access or disclose information about you, including the content of your communications, in order to: (a) comply with the law or respond to lawful requests or legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Microsoft or our customers, including the enforcement of our agreements or policies governing your use of the services; or (c) act on a good faith belief that such access or disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of Microsoft employees, customers, or the public. 

Information that is collected by or sent to Microsoft by CodePlex may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Microsoft or its affiliates, subsidiaries, or service providers maintain facilities. Microsoft abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

When you use software with Internet-enabled features, information about your computer ("standard computer information") is sent to the Web sites you visit and online services you use. Microsoft uses standard computer information to provide you Internet-enabled services, to help improve our products and services, and for statistical analysis. Standard computer information typically includes information such as your IP address, operating system version, browser version, and regional and language settings. In some cases, standard computer information may also include hardware ID, which indicates the device manufacturer, device name, and version. If a particular feature or service sends information to Microsoft, standard computer information will be sent as well.

The privacy details for each CodePlex feature, software or service listed in this privacy statement describe what additional information is collected and how it is used.

## Security of your information

Microsoft is committed to helping protect the security of your information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. 

## Changes to this privacy statement

We will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our products, services, and customer feedback. When we post changes, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this statement. If there are material changes to this statement or in how Microsoft will use your personal information, we will notify you either by posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how Microsoft is protecting your information.

## For More Information

Microsoft welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please [contact us](https://www.codeplex.com/site/contact). 

CodePlex Privacy  
Microsoft Corporation   
One Microsoft Way  
Redmond, Washington 98052 USA 

## Specific Features

The remainder of this document will address the following specific features:

## Registration

What This Feature Does: CodePlex registration allows you to create a User Account that you can use to upload new source code, participate in discussion forums, rate existing projects, and register issues. 

Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted: When you register, CodePlex will ask you to choose a User Name and Password, and will ask you to provide a valid email address. 

Use of Information: Your User Name will be used to identify each source code file, rating, discussion comment, or issue you post on the site. Your email address will be used to validate your account, and may also be used to allow other users to contact you. When another user contacts you, they will not see your email address. 

Choice/Control: You may not post to CodePlex without first registering, however if you chose not to register, you may still download projects. You may choose to Opt-Out of allowing other users to contact you by updating the contact preference in your CodePlex Profile.

## Profile

What This Feature Does: When you post new source code, participate in discussion forums, rate existing projects, and register issues, your post will be tagged with your User Name. Other users may click on your User Name to view your Profile. 

Information Collected, Processed, or Transmitted: Your User Name, the date you joined CodePlex, your Projects, and your recent Activities on the CodePlex site will be visible to users that view your Profile. If you choose to add a Personal Statement to your Profile, this will also be visible. 

Use of Information: Other users may view your profile to learn more about your activities on CodePlex. They may also use your Profile page to contact you if your Profile contact preference is set to enable other users to contact you. 

Choice/Control: You may choose to Opt-Out of allowing other users to contact you by updating the contact preference in your CodePlex Profile.
